Two techniques. One purely mechanical technique to free this space
right there.
And secondly, a global diaphragm technique, which is excellent for
children, babies, anyone, to restore expansion.
And here, I will guide you through a biodynamic practice.
We will work on this esophageal and diaphragmatic junction.
There is quite a lot of...
Nerve network; there are significant areas with the vagus trunk
which is here, you see.
So we'll do this gently.
But at the same time, by freeing this area, you’ll free a whole vagal area.
Here we can clearly see the right diaphragmatic portion and the left diaphragmatic portion.
We can clearly see what we call the pleura,
which is here.
And here, we have what we call a remnant, which
was once a valve, called Treitz and Leimer’s valve, located here.
They are here.
Then here, we have a small muscle, which
inserts on the diaphragm and on the peritoneum,
forming what we call a peroesophageal space.
An area of adaptability, of rebalancing in relation to
this diaphragmatic junction
found here, which continues after with the muscle of Treitz, which is the
ligament
that suspends the duodenum, number 3 or 4. The
body often organizes itself in a spiral shape,
the spiral is a powerful form; there are many spirals in the body.
The embryo develops in a spiral movement.
We use spirals to gain more strength.
Well, at this level, it is a spiral movement here.
Polarity, the spiral, in energy,
uses spirals to reach the peaks.
I position myself at the
junction, you see,
accessing the highest part I can have
on the stomach.
And then I descend,
I let it go down.
I will just ask you, it's a small test first,
to turn your head to the left.
Do you feel the sensation?
Okay? Come back.
Turn your head to the right.
You come back, turn your head to the left.
It’s limited on the left.
Very often,
this area here,
prevents proper neck rotation, so I’m going to position myself here and let it
fall back towards me
you let it drop like that, all limp, all limp, all limp, all limp, I let it go again,
I’m strong, you can confirm, there you go, again, let your head go too, there,
all limp.
And now, I will keep a point of support with my thumb, okay, all limp, I
let it go, and I will start to descend here, I go down.
I will go a bit deeper, I’m searching, I go down, there it is, I descend, gently,
I listen to the tissues, there, for example here, I need to go a bit like this, I
search, there I go down, very slowly, I observe your breathing, there,
at exhalation, I accumulate a bit, I go down, okay, there I hit
a little, it’s a bit hard now, so I’m going to go very gently, I make a good learning point,
then posteriorly, standing straight, to be stable, I keep my points here, if you
feel no pain, it goes very gently, very gently, I keep a bit of pressure because I have the
clothing, I go back down, there, hop, there I will gently ask her to
straighten up, very gently, very gently, for now it’s okay, stop,
you release, I suddenly have the hop coming up with me, you let yourself go, there,
I keep.
You rise slowly.
I hold, you come up.
Again.
Stop! You release.
There I rise.
You let go.
Here we go, you rise.
Again.
You grow. Stop! You release.
You release.
And a brake.
I’m going to look a bit further.
I rise and I go back down.
As it's painful,
it rises towards the gallbladder.
Yes, it works.
You rise slowly, it grows.
There, it grows, there.
And up to here.
I do this.
I take the
posterior part here, between my two hands.
I test it backward.
Let yourself go, really relax, please.
There, great.
Is it okay, not too painful, the gallbladder like that?
Do you feel the body or not?
There, it’s coming, did you feel it?
And it opens at the gallbladder level.
There, it just passed.
There, hop, I accompany.
There, very good.
Did you feel the pfff?
You’re sought through a posterior support.
And we place back; now you turn your head.
In this diaphragmatic issue, I explained that there was this retro-cavity of the
epiploons.
Do you remember that?
The retro-cavity of the epiploons.
There were these esophageal insertions, etc.
And now we’re going to perform a technique where we will go towards...
Don’t forget that to have...
Remember the ribs, the importance of the ribs with the diaphragm.
There is a significant concentration at this level.
Well, it’s a very simple technique.
We will come where the hole is.
You see a small hole, there.
And there, I come here and place my hand flat, like this.
And I will go towards the junction, towards the ribs at levels 7, 8, 9,
there.
You see, something like this.
I slide my hand underneath.
And I place it, I really lay it flat.
Then I come with my hand here, like this.
And there, I let go.
I let go like this.
I do like this.
You see?
There, I have a little lever arm.
And this is a really important area.
It’s a major crossroads of tension.
We can release it.
It will release the whole junction
It will also release the whole zone
of Treitz muscle, etc.
And especially this relationship.
And now, she will feel, now,
I will focus on another sensation, you see.
I will search in the totality.
There, I touch the whole body now.
You have the retro-gastric pouch which is very important to mobilize.
Often, the ulcers are posterior, and you have the retro-gastric pouch,
so the posterior space of the stomach,
which actually needs this mobility for a good journey.
For good function, it must be free.
If it is not free, it has not been released in relation to the diaphragm.
The esophagus and stomach are the first in relation with the base of the skull.
And they also have this relationship with the posterior mesogastrum,
with the aorta and the left branches.
It gives us the warmth that rises and then goes down.
I will now enter into another level; this is when I access the strength of embryonic development,
in the power, I observe the breathing, there I
know where it stands, I await the gate.
There, I've just passed.
I don't know if you will perceive a difference.
When I focus on the A zone, there's immediate facial work,
I want to
give more space between the diaphragm and the pulmonary zone,
as if I were
being led to descend.
At the same time, one must know that on a peritoneal level, in
the organization of the peritoneum, I am at the first point of support of the peritoneum.
This means that the left colic angle is the first fixed point of
overall peritoneal development.
So it’s the first point of support.
I will focus on this support point now, and I will shift to the point of
mobility.
The most mobile point.
It’s at the level of the cecum. It’s the last to settle. So here
I have a cecum,
to see a bit how it is positioned. Support point. And
between my two hands, I have the whole axis of rotation,
all the movements of the colonic framework that has settled like
this. And the diaphragm,
it works on that. And within this, I have all the spaces of type...
the falciform ligament, the greater omentum, then
you can choose; the body chooses for you, a
work.
So here I can say that there is a slight tension on the falciform ligament,
especially its right leaf,
with sometimes
the expression
of a
gentle anger
that is there, that is empty
it’s as if
She feels much more her posterior support, and at the same time, a release here, a small
support.
And at the same time here, there you go, it’s a work that is done in a synchronicity
on her tent,
on her falx cerebri, at the level of the Christagalus.
We will work on the sinus, on the sinus above.
We will open, there, her anger
expresses itself for me, it’s my journey; her anger was
related to an inability at some point to express herself.
It can be around 7-8 years.
That’s where the tissue takes me.
It may be cleared a bit.
Something she could not say or wanted to say but didn’t say to herself.
Seizing the protocol between when you entered biodynamics and before.
I focused on the whole, then I entered another,
I left thoracic breathing, I entered into the space,
and I kept it open, and then the body guided me,
it led me to two support points, then it moved,
and then flashes appeared of tensions,
and since I know all the synchronies well, I departed on some infractions.
I felt points, and I let go into my words.
It was the moment when you began the totality until the point you searched for the gate that opened.
In the process you described to us this morning, before that...
I will give you the key, but I give it in an initiatory way.
Okay.
I dive into the water.
I listen to the movement.
I feel the movement.
I seek balance.
Once I have found the balance point, I will listen behind the
silence.
Before we start, let’s share a bit of what you felt about the other approach.
When I gave the word and felt it was received,
I perceived many cells that started to receive and
exchange all at once.
And it was when you said, there, it’s good.
I thought that was it.
And that’s nice when all the cells make a chin-chin together.
A somewhat similar sensation, just as when I said the word.
There was really a cellular response from the
tissues.
This is called ignition.
So here, the approach is that we will take the diaphragm,
as we have seen with the costopleuro-pulmonary recess.
We will give this space to the diaphragm.
But there are mistakes we must not make in the hand position.
I must have a fairly balanced sensation between my hands.
The mistake not to commit here is to press like this, pressing on the head.
So that’s really over time, I can say, it’s true.
Having a good support on your elbows, and then you need to imagine you’re eating garlic.
And you take the right space; it’s really important to take good space.
In this practice, I will guide you into a meditative state.
I don’t want it here. Now, I will just place you in position.
And you try just a bit to...
You tell me a bit about your feeling of the position like that.
A touch that is very light, with a lot of warmth,
that is very global, and ultimately, I feel that it’s just at the foot.
At the same time, I really have this sensation that I am taking this micro-crystalline field.
All this stuff, this small network; you have cells,
and on these cells, you have receptors.
It creates a vast field.
For example, the largest concentration point of information of a glyco-
calyx,
is at the second duodenum level.
It’s the part of the intestine most informed.
And then it spreads all over the body, it’s like a field that encompasses everything; it allows you to
to connect, you see, I am on this field, I
tell you in meditation.